#### Miftakhul Aziz

Address: Kebayoran Lama, Jakarta Selatan, Phone: +6282249993937, Email: <u>miftakhull.aziz@gmail.com</u>, LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/miftakhullaziz</u>,

GitHub: github.com/mftakhullaziz

#### **Summary**

I am Aziz, a Software Engineering Backend at IT Consultant from Singapore with a place in the Indonesian region, my current work includes making Rest APIs for backend services, cleaning code, fixing bugs, updating features from the backend side, unit testing code, making scheduler with crontab, implementing new features and so on. I have expertise in the field of Software Engineering, the main programming languages are Java and Golang. Apart from that, I am also familiar with stack technology, spring-boot framework, SQL database, Kafka, Elasticsearch, Spark, Hibernate, and others. I graduated in Informatics Engineering from the Sumatra Institute of Technology in 2021 with a background in Data and Software Engineering. On the other hand, I have soft skills in terms of communication with the team, leadership, fast learner and never give up in solving problems, clean code, adapt quickly to new environments, and like to learn new things, especially in new things.

### **Experiences**

Aleph Labs

Jakarta
Software Engineers

July 2023 - Present

Currently working as a Software Development Engineer in the IT Consultant from Singapore, I joined in region Indonesia with a place in Jakarta Selatan. I join in the Backend Team for development project health care from client U By Prodia for building ecommerce app for Prodia.

Jobs responsibilities:

- Development backend service for produces restful API for consumption in mobile, iOS, and web.
- Enhancement existing restful API service with a related new requirement from product team.
- Development backend payment service and integrate with external payment gateway, include notifications, email notification, and handle callbacks.
- Fixing bugs in existing code or bugs in features development.
- Create or enhance unit testing to test new function or existing function with new update, and the main purpose is for coverage code at the Sonar before merge or pull request into main branch.
- Handling end to end logger for backend service using Log4j2.
- Enhancement feature in middleware apps.
- Code reviews.

Implement software architecture for new services.

Technologies Stack: Java, Software Architecture, Microservices, Design Patterns, AWS, MongoDB, NoSQL, Reactive Programming, Spring Boot, Spring Framework, Spring Web Flux, Spring Data Mongo, Object Oriented Programming, Mockito Unit Testing, Reactor.

## Advotics Supply Chain SaaS

Jakarta

**Software Engineers** 

March 2022 - July 2023

Currently working as a Software Development Engineer in Start Up Supply Chain on the team Fast Track, Identity, Platform, and Data team to make features in the Backend service. here is the work I didand the technology stack used.

Jobs responsibilities:

- Develop Extract Transform Load (ETL) for data migration needs from OLTP to OLAP environment.
- Develop restful API, in the Backend service for use on internal API and external API.
- Enhancement of the existing API with new conditions that are adjusted to feature needs for the backend service side.
- Analysis of bugs and fixing a bug in all environment development, sandbox, user agreement testing, production, and production-gold.
- Building unit testing in existing API or new API development with Mockito and JUnit.
- Creation of custom report with scheduler using crontab in all environments.
- Query SQL Optimization.
- Implement clean architecture and clean code, local and Integration testing.
- Deployment already new feature from development into integration environment.

Technologies stack: Java Programming Language, SQL, Python, Bash Script, Hibernate, Java Persistence API, QueryBuilder, Query DSL, Elasticsearch, Amazon web service, Spring Boot Framework, Git Version, Reactor, Reactive Programming, Redis.

# Indonesia Indicator

Jakarta

**Software Engineers** 

April 2021 - March 2022

Indonesia indicator is a consulting company engaged in Big Data Intelligence. While at IndonesiaIndicator I worked as a Backend Engineer with the data team. here is the work I did and the technologystack used.

Jobs responsibilities:

- Building service for cleaning data sources with format csv and excel using Python engine.
- Create social network analysis for analytical product, and modelling the data for SNA using machine learning.
- Create crawling service for streaming crawling data using Apache Kafka from media social.
- Create service for mapping and migration data sources to Elasticsearch, I elastic the data will be definewith a two main index is raw data dan clean data index.
- Development service for produces restful API using Spring boot using data source from elastic, the API from this service will be consume in web service analytical.
- Deployment into production environments and monitoring web services with alerting from

telegram.

- Fixing bugs in existing code or in production environments.
- Implements Software Architecture with using architecture layered architecture.

Technologies stack: Java, Python, Spring Boot Framework, Gitlab, Restful API, Elasticsearch Kibana, Apache Spark, Machine Learning, Kibana, Hadoop, Kafka.

Ustreet Transportation Full Stack Engineers **Bandar Lampung** 

October 2020 - March 2021

I joined UStreet as a backend engineer, here is the work I did and the technology stack used. Developing an online motorcycle taxi application that is domiciled in the city of Bandar Lampung, UStreet itself is a Start Up engaged in online motorcycle taxi services. Jobs responsibilities:

- Building architecture relational database.
- Create new features in backend service and mobile app.
- Enhance existing features in backend service and mobile app.
- Fixing bugs production.
- Create OTP authentication service.

Technologies Stack: Java, Android Studio, Retrofit, MySQL, Google Cloud Platform, PHP Laravel, Google PlayStore Service.

Sumatera Institute of Technologies Data Science Laboratory Assistant

Bandar Lampung January 2020 – April 2020

Become a practicum assistant for data science courses, and teach the following data science and provide training in laboratory informatics engineering as data science with a python and machine learning.

Jobs responsibilities:

- Provide related practicum material data science with analysis exploration, data cleaning, machine learning, deep learning, modelling, data visualization, and implementing a cripsdm methodology in practicum class.
- Creating a data science module with a python programming and module machine learning for analytical and training model.
- Provide a related practicum material machine learning modelling by applying several methods such asclassification and clustering.
- Help and provide services consultation for data science class students to complete the related big task datascience courses.

Technologies Stack: Python, Jupiter-Lab, Pandas, NumPy, Scikit Learn, Anaconda, Classical Algorithm Machine Learning, Darknet for Deep Learning, Convolutional Neural Networks.

Sumatera Institute of Technologies

Bandar Lampung

Internet of Things Laboratory Assistant

August 2019 – December 2019

Become a practicum assistant for Internet of things (IOT) courses, and teach the following IOT and provide training in laboratory informatics engineering as IOT with a C programming and Arduino.

Jobs responsibilities:

- Creating an embedded system, and IOT module for a system with C programming.
- Provide related practicum material Arduino, Node MCU, and others module are used for practicum in IOT class.
- Provide related practicum material cloud computing such as GCP.
- Help and provide service consulting for IOT class students to complete the big task related to IOT courses.

Technologies Stack: C Programming, Arduino, Arduino-IDE, Node MCU, GCP, Module Sensors.

Cyber Labs Bandung

Full Stack Engineers Intern

May 2019 - August 2019

I carried out an internship program at an IT consultant in the city of Bandung, namely Cyber Labs Official, I joined the Full Stack Engineer team playing the technology stack, Laravel. Jobs responsibilities:

- Creating an e-commerce web application backend and frontend for clients by implementing the Laravel framework and MySQL.
- Implementing live chat on an e-commerce client web app.
- Creating a backend service with restful API for use on administrator panel and web clients.
- Creating search engine features for search products in web e-commerce clients.

Technologies Stack: PHP Laravel, JavaScript, MySQL, Live chat clients.

# **Technologies Stack**

Java **Bash Scripting** Golang **Reactive Programming Python** Apache Spark **Spring Framework** Swagger Open API Go Gin Framework **Spring Cloud** Apache Kafka Amazon Web Service **Hibernate Persistence** Spring Web Flux Spring Data JPA **R2DBC Non-Blocking RDBMS** Query Native & Query Builder **Spring Reactor** Mockito & Junit **Design Patterns** GitHub, Gitlab, Bitbucket Database (MySQL, PostgreSQL, MariaDB) **Software Architecture** NoSQL (MongoDB, Elasticsearch, Redis, Kibana)

#### **Educations**

Sumatera Institute of Technologies Bachelor of Informatics Engineering Bandar Lampung August 2016 – March 2021

Graduate GPA: 3.28 of 4.00

<u>Thesis:</u> Identification Number Plat Police on The Vehicle Using Deep Learning Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs).

<u>Description:</u> Applying the Deep Learning Model Residual Network 50 (ResNet-50) Algorithm to detect objects on vehicle plates. Applying the You Only Look Once (YOLO-V3) Variant Deep Learning Algorithm with Dark-Net to detect objects on vehicle plates. Applying Open CV to segment the characters on the vehicle plate. Applying the Mobile-Net V2 Variant Convolutional Neural Network Model to classify the characters on the vehicle plate.

### **Organizations**

Sumatera Institute of Technologies Electrical and Informatics Students Association Staff of The External Department Bandar Lampung August 2018 – October 2019

<u>Description:</u> I joined HMEI for the position of Staff of The External, where I have a role to create a team work program which includes HMEI's relationship with other associations, especially outside the campus, in addition to developing community service programs with direct impacts such as technology socialization, helping doing reforestation of mangrove forests in the coastal area of Lampung, providing learning for elementary school children related to information technology.

Sumatera Institute of Technologies Internet Of Things Community Lead of Research and Development Bandar Lampung
August 2019 – December 2020

<u>Description:</u> I joined HMEI for the position of Staff of The External, where I have a role to create a team work program which includes HMEI's relationship with other associations, especially outside the campus, in addition to developing community service programs with direct impacts such as technology socialization, helping doing reforestation of mangrove forests in the coastal area of Lampung, providing learning for elementary school children related to information technology.

Sumatera Institute of Technologies Informatics Student Association Head of Extra Campus Division Bandar Lampung October 2019 – December 2020

<u>Description:</u> Then the organizational experience on campus was being part of HMIF, at that time HMEI which included Informatics and Electrical was divided into study programs because the members were enough to establish their own association, after HMIF was formed I was appointed Head of the Extra Campus Division, I have staff who help HMIF development of this division. my friends and I developed work programs such as sitting with lecturers to share

related technology topics, collaborating with other groups to share knowledge and so on.

## Certifications

Golang Developer (Udemy)

Spring Boot Design Patterns (Udemy)

Deep Learning Specialization (Coursera)

End To End Machine Learning on GCP (Coursera)

Restful API Intermediate (Hacker Rank)

Credential-7dfb4253

Credential-4f89f44c

Credential-ZGH2Y2D

Credential-UV473JYS

Credential-UV473JYS